Me

My name is Nicolay, and I'm a programmer. I didn't fully realise this until I was about 22 years old, but after my epiphany I've devoted more than half of my waking hours to program computers to do my will, with varying success.

In 2013 I graduated from the Norwegian University of Science and Technology with an M.Sc. in computer science. During my studies I spent about 10 hours weekly in extra-curricular activites (including being the webmaster for a large-scale IT conference and sitting on the board for a student festival). Additionally I spent one year abroad, attending the computer science graduate program at the University of California, San Diego where I graduated with a GPA of 3.902.

Contact

Email: nicohvi@gmail.com

Web: <u>nico.cool</u>
Github: nicohvi

Employment

Senior technology consultant
BEKK Consulting, 2016 - present

Technology consultant
BEKK Consulting, 2013 - 2015

Summer intern
Capra Consulting, 2012

Summer intern Inspera, 2011

Education

Master of Science, Computer Science Norwegian University of Science and Technology August 2008 - June 2013

Graduate Program Exchange Student -Computer Science University of California, San Diego August 2011 - June 2012

Skills

Web development javascript, sass/less, react.js, elm, ruby on rails, ruby, .NET MVC, .NET OWIN, node.js, express.js, electron

Systems / app development ruby, c#, node.js, puppet, unix, docker, bash, xamarin, postgreSQL, rabbitMQ, nginx, apache

Paradigms

Functional programming, reactive programming, pair programming, test-driven development

Other Photoshop, Illustrator

Side projects

Ballot

Ballot is a website for creating and voting on polls which can be shared with others.

Stump

Stump is a minimal logging wrapper for rack-based web applications.

Moviepicker

Moviepicker is a small website which suggests movies for you based on the rotten tomatoes API and IMDB ratings. It was created to demonstrate functional reactive programming.